Don't let the fancy clothes fool you.
Mr. Deeds is a comedy, romance film directed by Steven Brill.
When Longfellow Deeds, a small-town pizzeria owner and poet, inherits $40 billion from his
deceased uncle, he quickly begins rolling in a different kind of dough.
Moving to the big city, Deeds finds himself besieged by
opportunists all gunning for their piece of the pie.
Babe, a television tabloid reporter, poses as an innocent
small-town girl to do an exposé on Deeds.
Longfellow Deeds, played by Adam Sandler.
Babe Bennett, played by Winona Ryder.
Emilio Lopez, played by John Turturro.
Marty, played by Allen Covert.
Chuck Cedar, played by Peter Gallagher.
Mac McGrath, played by Jared Harris.
Deeds is a 2002 American comedy film directed by Steven Brill, written by
Tim Herlihy, and produced by Sid Ganis and Jack Giarraputo.
It stars Adam Sandler in the title role, alongside Winona Ryder, Peter
Gallagher, Jared Harris, Allen Covert, Erick Avari, and John Turturro.
The film is a remake of the 1936 Frank Capra film Mr.
Deeds Goes to Town, which itself was based on the 1935 short
story "Opera Hat" by Clarence Budington Kelland.
It tells the story of a pizzeria owner who learns that he
is the heir of a late multi-billionaire.
Produced by Columbia Pictures, New Line Cinema, Sandler's production company
Happy Madison Productions in association with Out of the Blue...
Entertainment, Mr.
Deeds was released in the United States by Sony
Pictures Releasing on June 28, 2002.
While financially successful, the film received negative reviews.
The film explores themes of new york city, love letter,
new hampshire, liar, city country contrast.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.